Ioryogi-san. It's autumn.
It smells like autumn.
Huh? Smells like autumn?
What does autumn smell like?
A bit smoky yet sunny, it gives you
this soothing feeling inside,
or is it more an exciting feeling inside.
A smell that gives you a sort of nostalgic feeling.
You have no memory yet you
recognize the smell of autumn?
Ioryogi-san!
What is it?
I wonder what that is.
Incredible...
Kobato.
What should I do?
Even the most obvious of things
Are always such a challenge
I want to laugh when I'm happy
And sing whenever I want
Is all
They say my dreams will come true someday
But when will "someday" come?
I can't wait forever
On "1, 2, 3!" I'll spread open my arms
And let the light gather around me
Where is it?
Please tell me what I can do
I make the most of getting hurt
And run with all my might
Despite how many dozens of times I fall
And start crying
I surprise myself
In how much I believe in tomorrow
...Angel and the Protector.
I have never seen such an
impressive ginkgo tree.
It is autumn indeed. Isn't it, Ioryogi-san?
What's wrong? You don't seem well.
Hey, Kobato!
Yes?
Take a look at this! Do you understand
the meaning of this?!
Umm... When autumn comes, the leaves get all
dressed up and dance in the wind...
We are not talking about fantasyland!
Kobato! What is your wish?!
Um...
Don't tell me you've forgotten!
I-It's to go to this place I want to go!
Well then, in order for your wish
to come true, what will you do?
Oh! Um! I'm going to collect kompeito!
And what must you do to
collect these kompeito?!
I will heal the broken hearts of people!
When must you do this by?!
By the time four seasons have passed!
How many seasons do you have remaining?
Two, sir!
How much have you collected?
Um...
About this much... sir...
Kobato?
Yes?
That place you wish to go.
You do know where it is, I presume.
Yes.
Is that so.
Hey watch it! You almost lost your hat!
Yes...
Give me a break...
Good morning.
Forget it then! I hate you, Toshihiko!
Wh-What's going on?
Don't tell people you hate them!
Yuzuru and Toshihiko were fighting
over some building blocks and...
I need a triangle for my train but
Toshihiko hogged two of them!
But I need two triangles to make a square!
Are there no more square blocks?
Th-Then let's all cooperate and make
something big together like a castle or...
I quit!
If you can't take care of them,
I'm not letting you use them.
What?!
See if I care! The toys here suck anyway!
Yeah, that's right! They're all old and dirty!
They should be thrown out!
Fujimoto, you mustn't!
Don't be mad Teacher Fujimoto!
Hey!
Hey! Kobato!
Huh? Ioryogi-san?
I just heard Ioryogi-san's voice,
but I don't see him anywhere.
Ioryogi-san!
You idiot!
What's the big idea getting all moody anyway?!
You think that's going to help
you gather kompeito?!
You're right. But...
Kobato.
Fujimoto just left for work. Is something wrong?
He left without saying a word.
That's not like him.
I wonder what happened.
Um...
What is it?
I see.
So that's what happened.
Fujimoto was not angry.
That was a look of sadness.
But I didn't notice that right away.
It's not your fault Kobato. And it isn't his either.
Huh?
It would be nice if the children
didn't have to make do.
If we could buy new things for
them to play with. But...
Things to play with?
I know! In that case, I know the perfect place!
The perfect place?
Um, where are you taking us?
To a fun place.
Wow!
This tree is huge! Great!
What a humongous tree!
Today we're going to collect fallen leaves.
And when we get back, we'll use
the leaves to draw pictures.
Draw pictures?
Do you see all the different shapes
and colors of the leaves?
Let's see what kind of pictures
we can make with them!
I'm going to collect a bunch!
Me too!
Ms. Sayaka look! Isn't this leaf pretty?
Oh my!
It's for you!
One for you too, Kobato!
Are you sure?
We're sorry.
Um...
About the building blocks...
Can you promise that you'll take
good care of them from now on?
I'll take good care!
Also, isn't there something you need
to say after you've had a fight?
Sorry...
I'm sorry...
You are to apologize to Fujimoto later too, okay?
I'm going to bring Teacher Fujimoto
a whole bunch of leaves!
Oh good. They've made up.
The children hardly ever fight.
Perhaps our anxiety is rubbing off on them.
Not that face, Ms. Sayaka!
You look best when you're smiling!
Thank you.
With a long face, happiness will
just run away, won't it?
Yes. Just smile. Keep smiling.
This is amazing. It looks as
though the light is on fire.
Yes.
It's beautiful. It gives me a very peaceful feeling.
Move away, please.
We don't want you to get hurt.
Um. What's about to happen here?
We're cutting down that tree tomorrow
so we've come to set up a fence.
Are you saying that you're going
to cut down this ginkgo?
What?! Why?!
There have been complaints from the neighbors.
They want it removed because it's a disturbance.
No way! It's such a magnificent tree! So grand!
Too grand. The falling leaves are out of control.
Besides, redevelopment construction
is due to begin soon.
Now get out of the way, please.
Ioryogi-san?
Huh?
What does redevelopment mean?
That's when they tear down old buildings
and destroy parts of the city
to make room for new stuff.
That's redevelopment?
Yeah.
Does that mean old things are bad and
there's no use for them anymore?
Not necessarily.
But it is true that there are more
people who appreciate new things.
Hey. It's not time for kindergarten yet.
I'm going to go and ask them.
Huh?
I'm going to ask them not to
cut down the ginkgo tree.
What? Wait a minute!
I'm sure if I ask them they'll...
Kohaku?
Good morning Kobato, Ioryogi-san.
Are you worried about the ginkgo tree too?
Huh?
Old things are in trouble
because of redevelopment.
Is that right?
But I'm going to ask them properly,
so there's nothing to worry about!
Is that so?
I don't get why there's nothing to worry about.
Oh? This fence wasn't here yesterday.
They say it's redevelopment.
Oh? Well, there's been talk about
it for quite some time now.
Such a grand ginkgo. But I guess it can't be
helped if it's going to make life easier for us.
Oh, what a shame. But redevelopment?
I like the sound of that.
I never noticed this huge tree here before.
It's so big it gives me the creeps.
No kidding.
Oops! Look at the time!
What's wrong, Kobato?
Nothing.
You're disappointed because
no one wants the tree.
That's not it at all.
Then what is it?
I think the ginkgo must be feeling lonely.
Lonely?
For years - maybe hundreds of years - the
tree's been here, watching this town.
Yet nobody cares about its well being.
It's all right Kobato.
Huh?!
The tree says it's not lonely.
You can understand? You know
how the tree is feeling?
Yes. In a way.
She tends to be absentminded,
but Kohaku is an angel after all.
Um... The ginkgo. What else is it saying?
It's very happy because yesterday, many small
people came to play. It was a lot of fun.
Is there... anything else that I can do?
It says thank you.
And also...
Goodbye.
It's okay! I'm going to ask
them not to cut you down!
It seems that's not what the tree wants.
Then I'm going to help the ginkgo tree move!
Huh? Hey!
Kobato!
Hey, now you're going completely overboard.
But... but...
But if I don't, the ginkgo will... this tree will...
I knew a wisteria tree that was
about as old as this ginkgo.
That wisteria said the same thing that
this ginkgo tree is telling me.
The same thing?
The biggest feeling of happiness
came from being able to protect.
Being able to watch over the people it loves.
Can you hear it? Can you
hear the ginkgo's song?
Yes. Slightly bittersweet, yet very, very kind.
By the water in the fall
And lurking in tree tops in winter
In each corner of the earth
Beauty everywhere in everything
When the sun goes down at night
Every night I shall offer a prayer
So that when tomorrow comes
I'll be here to welcome it in peace
The voices are calling to me
From way over yonder, from far I can hear
Voices of laughter
Voices of singing
Echoing voices of the wind
In happiness and in sadness
In all I behold and all that I live for
With my hand in your hand
Your hand in my hand
Together, we are one and whole
Hey!
The ginkgo tree...
Watch out, will you?! You could've gotten hurt!
I'm sorry.
It was ready to go.
Huh?
It's completely hollow.
It was ready to wither and die at any time.
It was hanging on, day by day, wasn't it?
Kohaku.
Do you think the ginkgo was happy?
Happy?
Yes, I'm sure.
At the end of its life, your song
was a beautiful send-off.
Ioryogi-san?
Huh?
Whose kompeito could this be?
Maybe Kohaku's? No, not likely.
Fujimoto's! No, of course not.
Might be that ginkgo tree.
What?
Plants have lives too.
If it's living, then it makes sense to think
that it has a soul that can be healed.
But I wasn't able to save it.
You sang that song to it.
Song?
Like Kohaku said. Your song was
a beautiful send-off.
You must have made it real
happy at the end of its life.
Do you think so?
Well, how does that look?
Fujimoto, won't you join us?
What's that?
Looks like... building blocks!
I made these from some branches
I got from that ginkgo.
From the ginkgo tree?
Wow, Fujimoto, you're awesome!
It's nothing.
Everybody! Fujimoto made us
some building blocks!
Wow! Awesome!
Toshihiko, Yuzuru. What do you say to Fujimoto
before playing with the blocks?
Teacher Fujimoto... We're sorry!
Y-Yeah...
Oh good! Everyone is friends again!
Hey, Teacher Fujimoto! Let's make
pictures with leaves together!
Uh, no... I'm...
Stick a ginkgo leaf here and you get
Ginkgoman from the planet of Fujimoto!
Huh?
Everyone dreams of flying
But they let gravity trick them
Honestly, everyone is already able to fly
I bet the reason that child looks so terribly sad
Is because he
Accidentally lost his shadow somewhere
In that case
If I could just tell you, "Thank you,"
And you laugh and reply, "Thank you"
That exchange would fill you with joy
It would make you feel so happy
There's nothing to worry about
Since we're together
It's strange how I'm crying
Even though I'm happy
Next episode
...Twilight Search.
Even though I'm happy
Next episode
...Twilight Search.